GABRIEL STEFANO VALIENTE

www.linkedin.com/in/gsvaliente gsvaliente.github.io +34 617-016-774

TIE: Y7395935T | gsvalient@gmail.com



ABOUT ME

Bilingual and multi-cultural MBA and Masters degree graduate, with over 3 years of working experience in the United States, Spain, and El Salvador. Recently certified as a NodeJs Back-end Developer and pursuing a career as a Full-Stack Developer. Motivated to combine my passion for programming and creating with my knowledge and expertise in Marketing. Seeking opportunities to continue growing my skills in a professional environment. Actively working on deepening my knowledge in Front-end Development. Open to opportunities in both fields of Marketing and Web Development. Able to work from Spain.

COMPETENCIES & SKILLS

- Native Spanish and English communication
- Cross-cultural marketing
- Customer analysis formulation
- Public relations management & execution
- Digital marketing strategy & execution
- · Paid digital media optimisation
- · Microsoft Suite certified
- Sales & lead management

- JavaScript ES6
- HTML5 & CSS
- Node.js & Express
- API creation & communication
- Understanding of REST Methodology
- Experienced with SCRUM & Git
- React.js & Redux
- Understanding of Unit Testing

WORK HISTORY

ALFA BETA CONSULTANTS

Marketing Associate | Barcelona, Spain | SEP 2020 - JUN 2021

- Supported creation of revised marketing strategy leveraging digital to respond to new COVID-19 operating reality.
- Developed digital marketing strategy and manage execution of paid and owned media including Google AdWords, website, and other platforms.
- Created paid digital marketing guidelines for franchised system to strengthen and optimise paid efforts across franchisees.
- Led creation of development strategy seeking new revenue streams for Aclam, a guitar company, looking to expand sources of income.
- Created execution roadmap of development strategy for Aclam including timetables, accountabilities and requirements to successfully expand revenues.

GLOBALPAY SERVICES

Marketing and Sales Coordinator | San Salvador, El Salvador | JUN 2018 - SEP 2019

- Assisted in increasing 15% of application user base by increasing media outlets
- · Managed Digital Marketing campaigns, with a focus on social media
- Cultivated relationships with new and potential customers to build leads
- Executed product launch for top-up application for the company
- Enhanced cost structure of sim card distribution to increase revenues

THE POWER GROUP

Account Coordinator | Dallas, TX, USA | OCT 2016 - FEB 2018

- Launched social media campaigns for agency clients with set KPIs
- Optimised website for customers through SEO and Google AdWords
- Organised campaigns for openings and activations
- Developed an industry analysis of competitors for strategy development
- Formed press releases and radio interviews

NASHER SCULPTURE CENTER

Digital Marketing Intern | Dallas, TX, USA | SUMMER 2017

MERCEDES-BENZ

Digital Marketing Intern | San Salvador, El Salvador | SUMMER 2016

EDUCATION

FRONTEND ONLINE BOOTCAMP

Zero to Mastery

Barcelona, Spain | ONGOING

BACKEND BOOTCAMP

IT Academy/ Barcelona Activa

Barcelona, Spain | FEB 2023

MASTER'S IN SOCIAL MEDIA MANAGEMENT

Barcelona Formación

Barcelona, Spain | AUG 2022

MBA IN INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS

EU Business School

Barcelona, Spain | JUNE 2020

BA IN MARKETING

West Virgina University

Morgantown, WV | MAY 2016